



## **Daniel Ponturo**

O Home: Liverpool, United Kingdom

**Phone:** (+44) 7842473844

**Website:** www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-ponturo-24b127177

**Gender:** Do not indicate **Date of birth:** 07/08/1999 **Nationality:** Italian

#### **ABOUT ME**

Software Engineer with experience in Web Development, using technologies such as React and Node. Fond of learning new things and always striving to learn from feedback in order to better myself and the people around me. Ready to adapt and always ready for a challenge.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# [ 01/08/2020 – Current ] **Associate Software Engineer**

#### Ivanti

City: Daresbury

**Country:** United Kingdom

- 1. Working on the development of an internal-use DevOps web app, using technologies such as React, Node.is, Kubernetes and Mongo DB, first as an intern (September 2020 - June 2021) and then currently as a full-time employee;
- 2. Supporting the crowd-sourcing process of the info hosted on the app, interfacing with Engineering teams;
- 3. Mentoring one of the team's new interns, helping get up to speed with working on the previously mentioned web app.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

[17/09/2018 - 19/07/2022]

## Computer Science with Software Development with a Year in Industry BSc (Hons)

#### University of Liverpool

Address: Liverpool, United Kingdom

Final grade: First Class Level in EQF: EQF level 6

#### **IOB-RELATED SKILLS**

### **Iob-Related Skills**

The following skills have been obtained through my work experience at Ivanti, as well as through academic and personal projects:

- 1. Experience in **creating Single Page Applications** (SPAs) using **React.js**, and designing their user interfaces;
- 2. Ability to **create server-side applications using Node.js**, as well their interfacing with user-side applications and databases;
- 3. Knowledge of Mongo DB, its interactions with web applications using REST APIs, as well as the Aggregation Framework;
- 4. Familiarity with the Azure DevOps (ADO) and GitHub APIs;
- 5. Understanding of **Kubernetes** clusters, **Docker** images, and **CronJobs**, along with the monitoring of the latter using both Kubectl and Lens;
- 6. Experience in working with and facilitating the use of the **DevOps practices**;
- 7. Basic experience in running Sprint meetings.

Moreover, I enjoy **learning new programming languages** as needed in a rapidly changing work environment, and try to brush up and improve my skills by following Microsoft and LinkedIn courses on a weekly basis.

## ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

#### **Team-working and Problem-solving skills**

**Good team-working and problem solving skills** gained while partaking in the daily activities of a young team of developers at Ivanti:

- As an active a member of the team since 2020, I was tasked with collaborating and mentoring one of the new interns who started their journey at the company in 2022;
- Tested and advanced my team-working abilities, not to mention understood how to manage the division of labour in a sub-team of two people, making sure task details and pre-requisites where as clear as possible, as well as the final goal achievable;
- My ability to explain problems in an easy to understand fashion also improved thanks to this experience.

## COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

#### **Communication and interpersonal skills**

**Very good communication skills** gained through my involvement in facilitating the crowd-sourcing of the information stored on the internal use web app me and the rest of the team develop:

- Being part of an Operations team as a developer tested my communication skills right from the start;
- Having to interact with the various Engineering teams throughout the whole of Ivanti, I managed to develop a good network of people and have a steady communication channel with them in order to provide them with the best service feasible;
- Building up on the communication knowledge gained through the crowd-sourcing and feedback gathering process, I was also able to correspond with the HRIT side of the company and organise various meetings in order to establish the prerequisites and develop an API to interface with the company's HR platform.

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other language(s):

### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

#### **Japanese**

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2** 

## INTERESTS AND FREE TIME

#### Interests and Free time

- 1. In my free time, I like to dedicate myself to studying the Japanese language. I have been a self-taught student of the language for a number of years now. The studying process has definitely helped me develop the ability to **handle tasks on my own**, as well as **resilience**. I have been practising my **spoken skills** on a weekly basis with a native speaker, and I feel my spoken production has tremendously improved thanks to the feedback I receive;
- 2. I also enjoy playing the bass guitar and skateboarding, while engaging with their respective communities.

3. I believe that, through these interests, I have been able to cultivate **good interpersonal skills**, having to **interface myself with a wide range of people**.

## **REFERENCES**

## References

References available on request.